{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"systolic arterial blood pressure is at least 60 mm Hg.",
					"body’s demand for oxygen is markedly increased.",
					"body’s temperature is considerably less than 98.6°F (37.0°C).",
					"heart rate is maintained at more than 100 beats/min."
				],
				"question": "An organ or tissue might better resist damage from hypoperfusion if the:",
				"source": "See Pathophysiology and Perfusion"
			},
			"back": "body’s temperature is considerably less than 98.6°F (37.0°C)."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"An intact system of blood vessels",
					"Adequate blood in the vasculature",
					"An effectively pumping heart",
					"The filtering of blood cells in the spleen"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following body systems or components is the least critical for supplying and maintaining adequate blood flow to the body?",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology of the Cardiovascular System"
			},
			"back": "The filtering of blood cells in the spleen"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Heart",
					"Brain",
					"Skeletal muscle",
					"Kidneys"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following organs can tolerate inadequate perfusion for two to three hours?",
				"source": "See Pathophysiology and Perfusion"
			},
			"back": "Skeletal muscle"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"poor general appearance.",
					"clinical signs and symptoms.",
					"the mechanism of injury.",
					"systolic blood pressure."
				],
				"question": "The severity of bleeding should be based on all of the following findings, except:",
				"source": "See External Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "systolic blood pressure."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"blood typically oozes from a vein.",
					"veins hold smaller blood volume.",
					"veins carry deoxygenated blood.",
					"veins are under a lower pressure."
				],
				"question": "External bleeding from a vein is relatively easy to control because:",
				"source": "See External Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "veins are under a lower pressure."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"splinting the extremity.",
					"keeping the patient warm.",
					"applying a tourniquet.",
					"applying chemical ice pack."
				],
				"question": "Internal bleeding into a fractured extremity is most often controlled by:",
				"source": "See Emergency Medical Care for External Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "splinting the extremity."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"cells.",
					"veins.",
					"venules.",
					"aorta."
				],
				"question": "Capillaries link the arterioles and the:",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology of the Cardiovascular System"
			},
			"back": "venules."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"at least 10% of the patient’s blood volume is lost.",
					"low fluid volume leads to inadequate perfusion.",
					"the clotting ability of the blood is enhanced.",
					"the patient’s systolic BP is less than 100 mm Hg."
				],
				"question": "Hypovolemic shock occurs when:",
				"source": "See External Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "low fluid volume leads to inadequate perfusion."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"should be assumed to be caused by a fractured septum.",
					"is a sign of a skull fracture and should not be stopped.",
					"is usually due to hypertension caused by the head injury.",
					"should be controlled by packing the nostril with gauze."
				],
				"question": "Bleeding from the nose following head trauma:",
				"source": "See Emergency Medical Care for External Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "is a sign of a skull fracture and should not be stopped."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"cyanosis.",
					"cellular death.",
					"hypoxemia.",
					"shock."
				],
				"question": "Hypoperfusion is another name for:",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology of the Cardiovascular System"
			},
			"back": "shock."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"ability of the systemic arteries to constrict as needed to maintain an adequate blood pressure.",
					"effective transfer of oxygen from the venules across the systemic capillary membrane walls.",
					"effective removal of carbon dioxide and other metabolic waste products from the body’s cells.",
					"circulation of blood within an organ in adequate amounts to meet the body’s metabolic needs."
				],
				"question": "Perfusion is most accurately defined as the:",
				"source": "See Pathophysiology and Perfusion"
			},
			"back": "circulation of blood within an organ in adequate amounts to meet the body’s metabolic needs."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"2 L",
					"1 L",
					"500 mL",
					"250 mL"
				],
				"question": "A fractured femur can result in the loss of ______ or more of blood into the soft tissues of the thigh.",
				"source": "See Internal Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "1 L"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"how rapidly he or she bleeds.",
					"how fast his or her heart beats.",
					"the part of the body injured.",
					"his or her baseline blood pressure."
				],
				"question": "The ability of a person’s cardiovascular system to compensate for blood loss is most related to:",
				"source": "See External Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "how rapidly he or she bleeds."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"weakness or dizziness.",
					"a heart rate over 120 beats/min.",
					"a low blood pressure.",
					"diaphoresis and pale skin."
				],
				"question": "In older patients, the first indicator of nontraumatic internal bleeding might be:",
				"source": "See Internal Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "weakness or dizziness."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"bruising only.",
					"widespread ecchymosis.",
					"pain and distention.",
					"significant hypotension."
				],
				"question": "Early signs and symptoms of intra-abdominal bleeding include:",
				"source": "See Internal Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "pain and distention."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"10%",
					"5%",
					"20%",
					"15%"
				],
				"question": "Significant vital sign changes will occur if the typical adult acutely loses more than ______ of his or her total blood volume.",
				"source": "See External Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "20%"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"a rapid, thready pulse.",
					"a decreasing blood pressure.",
					"dizziness upon standing.",
					"rapid, shallow breathing."
				],
				"question": "In nontrauma patients, an early indicator of internal bleeding is:",
				"source": "See Internal Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "dizziness upon standing."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"hematemesis.",
					"hemoptysis.",
					"hematuria.",
					"dyspnea."
				],
				"question": "Gastrointestinal bleeding should be suspected if a patient presents with:",
				"source": "See Internal Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "hematemesis."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Vacuum splint",
					"Sling and swathe",
					"Cardboard splint",
					"Air splint"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following splinting devices would be most appropriate to use for a patient who has an open fracture of the forearm with external bleeding?",
				"source": "See Emergency Medical Care for External Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "Air splint"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"elevating the injured extremity.",
					"applying local direct pressure.",
					"compressing a pressure point.",
					"packing the wound with gauze."
				],
				"question": "Most cases of external bleeding from an extremity can be controlled by:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment for External and Internal Bleeding"
			},
			"back": "applying local direct pressure."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-26",
		"label": "Chapter 26"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}